Contact

simijac2009@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/simi-jacob-233a9891 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing Cpr Certified BLS

Languages

Malayalam

Certifications

CPR

Neonatal Resuscitation Program

Simi Jacob

BSN RN, (MSN candidate)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Summary

Holds a Bachelor's of Science in Nursing degree from Texas Tech University Health Science Center in Lubbock. Specialized and graduated from a neonatal ICU residency in June 2016 and have been working in a Level III NICU ever since. I thoroughly enjoy what I do as a nurse and have learned a wealth of information within my last four years in bedside care. I am ready for my next challenge and am excited for the opportunities that are waiting for me in the medical field.

Experience

Seton Healthcare Family Float RN November 2018 - June 2020 (1 year 8 months) Austin, TX

Baylor Scott & White Health NICU Registered Nurse March 2018 - October 2018 (8 months) Rowlett, Texas

Parkland Hospital
Registered Nurse
January 2016 - February 2018 (2 years 2 months)
Dallas/Fort Worth Area

As a NICU nurse, we perform life-sustaining care on the smallest of premature infants. Duties include administering medications, monitoring vital signs and providing vital nutrients to newborns. Because most premature and sick newborns' lungs are not fully developed, we must ensure that infants are breathing and maturing properly. We work with upper-level nurses and physicians and assist in treatment plans and examinations. We keep, maintain and update records of the patient's care. In addition to medical care, NICU RNs communicate with and educate parents on day-to-day operations as well as home-care procedures.

Odessa Regional Medical Center NICU Nurse Intern November 2014 - August 2015 (10 months)

- -Responsible in working with a team of other healthcare professionals in providing critical care to premature and sick newborns.
- -Aside from providing around the clock care to these high risk patients, as a NICU nurse intern, we also offer support to the parents. This parental support can range from emotional encouragement to advising parents on how to take care of an infant when they return home.

Medical Center Hospital- Procare
Nurse Intern/Back Office Assistant
June 2014 - August 2015 (1 year 3 months)

Odessa, Texas

- Performs administrative and clinical duties, under the direct supervision of a registered nurse and delegation of a physician.
- Takes vital signs, performs labs, weight checks, and patient education as appropriate to each individual patient.
- Reviews and updates medication profile, allergies, and patient history
- Perform EKGs and assist with other back-office clinical procedures

Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center Student Assistant October 2013 - November 2014 (1 year 2 months)

Odessa, Texas

- Assists with all duties at the circulation desk such as check-in, checkout, renewing of medical library materials, processing interlibrary loans and reserves books.
- Supervise computer use and train others in the use of the computer as well as instructs patrons in the use of media and equipment and operates equipment, answers telephone, receives overdues, etc.
- Orients patrons to the library by informing them of services available and the location of media, by recommending media and by explaining use of the Public Access catalog.

Bank of America
Telephone Sales Associate
May 2011 - July 2012 (1 year 3 months)

Addison, Texas

- Responsible in effectively managing outbound calls to customers of Bank of America credit card accounts and informing them of the benefits and features of the product they have purchased 3, 6, and 9 months prior.
- Answers any questions regarding accounts and edits any information regarding the customer's profile.
- Takes credit line increase requests, transfers to appropriate departments regarding home loans, mortgages, and debit card questions.

MarketSource Inc.
Hewlett Packard Representative
June 2010 - December 2011 (1 year 7 months)
Dallas, Texas

- Visit various Hewlett Packard retailers and distributors in Dallas and ensure the full stock and proper display of all products and demo's related to the company.
- Involved in promoting sales within the accounts and teaching possible customers about our full line of products and services.
- Maintain proper knowledge and attend continuous training on new products and promotional events.

Education

Grand Canyon University

Master's degree, Nursing- Health Informatics · (2020 - 2022)

Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center
Bachelor's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2013 - 2015)

Texas Woman's University
Pre-Nursing Studies · (2010 - 2013)